<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Ecommerce</title>
      <link>/post/setting-up-ecommerce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/setting-up-ecommerce/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-e-commerce&#34;&gt;Setting up E-Commerce&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After everything I learned yesterday trying to set this stuff up on ritutoring.com I really have been reinvorgorated to pursue what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing. I can compare it to when I started working out and first noticed some more size/definition somehwere; I finally feel like I&amp;rsquo;m making progress and figuring things out, compartimentalizing and filing them away, gaining experience with the tools and systems used in industry, etc etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to what this post is actually about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I started looking into what would be the best way to let people pay online from the website for tutoring instead of having to fuck around with paypal invoices or cash r anything like that thats just bound to stab my lazy ass in the back if I went with it.
Started looking into other options, and went through a ton of them before finding things that would actually work. My current solution is to just let them pay and schedule time/date/location over email on an individual basis. If that gets out of hand I think I&amp;rsquo;ll have to migrate it to something that includes bookings, but I think that will be far enough in the future that waiting will be fine. I don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate enough volume for it to be an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the specifics, I ended up doing alot of research on different payment providers and eccomerce offerings. I ended up with Stripe; they seem like the most dedicated to technology and actually making things work properly and smoothly. I would have loved to use their builting Checkout thing but it wont work on a static Hugo website without jumping through hoops I dont want to deal with to setup some backend shit. I ended up sticking with stripe as the payment processor and link to my bank account, while using Snipcart on the front end for the actual shopping cart on the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think they also take some of my fucking money, but the customization and ease and scalability is probably worth it. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to intregare some kind of booking system with Snipcart itself, making make different products for each session and then only have 1 in stock per week? I&amp;rsquo;ll cross the bridge when it becomes an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;business-structure&#34;&gt;Business Structure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also spent alot of time doing research as to how I should setup this business legally.
The easiest and cheapest way seems to be just registering a DBA name with the town and hiring Lacey as a 1099 contractor and paying her hourly for whatever tutoring she does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may also be cool to try and get an LLC or something official sounding going that I can put on my resume and look ambitious, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for next summer (or I guess semester if things really take off? Not likely).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android App Dev (Java)</title>
      <link>/post/android-app-dev-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/android-app-dev-java/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After taking Gateway Computing: Java at Hopkins last semester, I have decided that making some kind of android app would probably be the best way to further my java knowledge and know-how, keep my coding skills sharp, and make something I can personally use and tht I can add to my resume as a project, and maybe even release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-app&#34;&gt;The App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think fitness tracker/helper type app would be a good first option. Its simple and straightforward in the right kind of way; I can make something that looks nice and is function and serves an actual concrete purpose. Its starting with my feet on the ground while giving my some room to expand upwards.
The name is still to be decided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;planned-features&#34;&gt;Planned Features&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally I am making this app for myself; I want to be able to program and track workouts and weights, see progress over time and stats like that, be able to input notes about certain workouts.
Maybe have a timer so a &amp;lsquo;workout&amp;rsquo; can be ran through and done with certain intervals. A long term calendar view, number of workouts until a cheat meal, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;progress-so-far&#34;&gt;Progress So Far&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I have been reading through some &amp;lsquo;first java app&amp;rsquo; type tutorials. Understanding the file structure of apps in general, the terminology, the way things are structured nd put together, dealing with all the different android sizes and distributions and features (Not something I have considered up until now), and other things of that nature.
My goal is to finish the tutorial I&amp;rsquo;ve been following and then just jump into making my app, just starting slow with the implementations, using git for version control, doing things right hopefully. Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Linux Fedora and Mint</title>
      <link>/post/installing-linux-fedora-and-mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/installing-linux-fedora-and-mint/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2019-05-17-installing-linux-fedora-and-mint_files/mint-leaves-image-mint-mint-leaves-png-image-and-clipart-for-png-mint-leaves-260_261.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mint leaf&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-linux-mint-fedora&#34;&gt;Installing Linux Mint &amp;amp; Fedora&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been hearing for years about the supposed benefits of working in a Linux operating system for programming and even as a regular computer user. I&amp;rsquo;ve always used Windows as my main desktop, from XP to 10. A few years ago I installed Ubunut on my desktop to try and dual boot it, but lost interest.
As I&amp;rsquo;m still thinking that I will pursue computer science, it would porbably be a good idea to get farmiliar with working in Linux sooner than later, so here I am :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;research&#34;&gt;Research&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set out to find some kind of balance between the regular GUI desktop enviornment I was farmiliar with, while also being able to learn some of the idiosyncracies of Linux (mainly just working in a CLI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first distro I installed was Fedora, but after trying to instlal a number of packages that would have been reuqired to run the software stack I use to run publish for this website, I switched to Mint.
Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s my fault and I just did not set something up properly, but I found Mint to be a much smoother ride while also teaching me more about what I&amp;rsquo;m doing than I felt I was learning in Fedora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-i-ve-learned-so-far&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve Learned So Far&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I have to apologize to everyone who I made fun of for using Linux, now I see its utility as an ultra custominzable and minimal environemnt. Whenever I go back to using windows on my desktop it feels bloated in comparison to how spartan Mint is.
Ive installed everyhing I need to publish this website, some of it from .deb simple installers and others through the command line, and pretty much have everything working now (even though I had to find some alternative programs to use i.e. GitKraken instead of Guthub Desktop and Remarkable instead of Caret or Typora for a markdown editor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;going-forward&#34;&gt;Going Forward&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to learn more about the nitty gritty and see the full potential of the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning HTML: Basics</title>
      <link>/post/learning-html-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/learning-html-basics/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I have created and setup a decent rough outline of my tutoring website (along with buying ritutoring.com and wlhood.com), but I want to edit the theme files to make it look better. I beleive the edits I want to make would be done through CSS, but the two go hand in hand and I’d rather just start with the foundations and learn HTML and CSS and get into good habits before I jump into the weeds more with Java and whatever else I want to get into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m rationalizing this by thinking of the value of having a professional website as a portfolio to show off my skills, and also to force myself in this self-study journey to take notes I can come back to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;basic-html&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Basic HTML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTML is a &lt;strong&gt;tag-based&lt;/strong&gt; language, it is built with &lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;. Elements have &lt;strong&gt;start and end tags&lt;/strong&gt;, the end tag being identical except it starts with a forward slash. Elements can be within elements.
Some tags like img or br are &lt;strong&gt;empty tags&lt;/strong&gt;, there is only one (see below examples).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;!DOCTYPE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text &amp;amp; Images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;doctype&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;!DOCTYPE&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top line of the html file has this code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signals that the file is written in HTML5 code.
The entire body of the html document is surround by the tag html.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt; 

&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;structure&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Structure&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual page is split into the head, the meta data of the page, and the body, the actual body of the page.
Metadata is information about the page that isnt displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
   
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
   
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;text-images&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Text &amp;amp; Images&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the header you can set the title, the text displayed on the browser tab.
Within the body, titles and subtitles can be made with h1 through h6, largest to smallest. Regular text can be written within paragraphs, p. A line break can be inserted anywhere with br. Images in the same folder as the html document can be inserted with img. A horizontal rule (horizontal line to speerate content) can be inserted with hr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;title&amp;gt; Title &amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
   
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt; Biggest Header&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;h6&amp;gt;Smallest Header&amp;lt;/6&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; Regular paragraph text&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; Broken &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; Paragraph&amp;lt;/P&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;hr&amp;gt;
      
      &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;example.png&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;example alt text&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; height=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the img tag, src signifies the image file name, alt represents the text that will show if for some reason the image cannot be displayed. Width and height set the width and height of the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text within p tags cannot be formamted with spaces and line breaks without tags. Pre tags can be used to retain line breaks and extra spaces between words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;
      Line         breaks
      and     spaces    maintained
      &amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;
      
      &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
      Line       breaks   
      and    spaces   NOT   maintained
      &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;lists&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lists&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can make two types of simple lists, ordered and unordered. Unordered lists are marked with bullet points, ordered lists are marked with increasing numbers.
ul and ol determine unordered/ordered, and every list item is denoted with li.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
   
      &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; Ex List Item &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
      
      &amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;
         &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; Ex List Item &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;
      
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;####Style
Color, font, and size can be set with the &lt;strong&gt;style&lt;/strong&gt; attribute. &lt;strong&gt;Attributes&lt;/strong&gt; go within the start tag of an element, and effect only that element. Other attributes are img.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style’s use CSS to change color, size, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lang: Attribute for html to set language
title: Attribute for p to create tooltip
background-color: Attribute for body to set background color&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attribute text should be in double quotes, or single quotes if neccesary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;p style=&amp;quot;color: red&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Colored Text &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;p title=&amp;quot;Tooltip when hovered&amp;quot;&amp;gt; Paragraph &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
   &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating This Website</title>
      <link>/post/creating-this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-this-website/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;This simple personal website was made following this book: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34;&gt;blogdown: Creating Websites with R Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using it as a simple, easily managed portfolio and personal website, documenting personal projects and other content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;technologies-used&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Technologies Used:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown (Using Typora)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R (Using R Studio)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netlify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All posts are written in Typora, my preferred Markdown editor. Markdown is a simple markup language, that I think makes exceptionally clean and modern websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website is generated using blogdown and hugo, as described in the mentioned book. The theme is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;, which again I think is lightweight and stylish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the website is edited or new posts created, the files are updated in a Github repository that is then linked to Netlify and automatically updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of writing this, my next aim is to further customize and optimize the site for my purposes, and to purchase and setup a domain name, along with launching a similar website for my planned tutoring business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
