<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Portfolio</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Linux Fedora and Mint</title>
      <link>/post/installing-linux-fedora-and-mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/installing-linux-fedora-and-mint/</guid>
      <description>Installing Linux Mint &amp;amp; Fedora I have been hearing for years about the supposed benefits of working in a Linux operating system for programming and even as a regular computer user. I&amp;rsquo;ve always used Windows as my main desktop, from XP to 10. A few years ago I installed Ubunut on my desktop to try and dual boot it, but lost interest. As I&amp;rsquo;m still thinking that I will pursue computer science, it would porbably be a good idea to get farmiliar with working in Linux sooner than later, so here I am :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning HTML: Basics</title>
      <link>/post/learning-html-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/learning-html-basics/</guid>
      <description>I have created and setup a decent rough outline of my tutoring website (along with buying ritutoring.com and wlhood.com), but I want to edit the theme files to make it look better. I beleive the edits I want to make would be done through CSS, but the two go hand in hand and I’d rather just start with the foundations and learn HTML and CSS and get into good habits before I jump into the weeds more with Java and whatever else I want to get into.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating This Website</title>
      <link>/post/creating-this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-this-website/</guid>
      <description>This simple personal website was made following this book: blogdown: Creating Websites with R Markdown
I am using it as a simple, easily managed portfolio and personal website, documenting personal projects and other content.
Technologies Used:  Markdown (Using Typora) R (Using R Studio) Github Netlify  All posts are written in Typora, my preferred Markdown editor. Markdown is a simple markup language, that I think makes exceptionally clean and modern websites.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>